### Ernesto Lopez

**Contact:** (856) 343-7875 | <u>titolopez44@yahoo.com</u>

## **Summary:**

Aspiring web developer, fortunate to have received a crash course in business over ten years; with experience in warehouse operations, sales, customer service, catalog management systems, logistics, distribution, vendor relations, buying, inventory management, marketing efforts and ecommerce software. Grew with RevZilla.com as a start-up from 10 employees to over 1,000, \$20M in revenue to over \$500M, multiple organization changes and annual big ticket challenges. Still along for the ride and hoping to further advance the experience of the motorcycle enthusiast.

**Traits:** Inquisitive listener, ultimate solution seeker, sharp attention to detail

Skills: Excel user (functions, etc), Javascript, Html/CSS, Adobe Ps/Ai,

# **Employment:**

RevZilla.com

Feb 2014 - Current, Buyer

- Curated brands and product selection
- Adapted low-tech, small vendors to our system and processes
- Adapted special order products to fit our customer service model
- Created and implemented Vendor Agreements
- Negotiated margins by leveraging high growth potential and value driven efforts
- Managed vendor relationships and expectations
- Created and managed purchase orders
- Coordinated marketing & on-site ad efforts
- Managed inventory levels

### Sep 2011 - 2013, Logistics Associate

- Managed distribution queues of all customer and vendor orders
- Followed up on overdue customer drop ships with vendors
- Followed up on overdue stock orders
- Coordinated with customer service to manage customer expectations on fulfillment guarantees
- Implemented vendor on-boarding process

## Sep 2011 - 2014, Catalog Associate

- Cataloged accessories and vehicle specific parts for sale on our site
- Managed and sold blemished/used inventory on company eBay account

## Feb 2011 - 2018, Revzilla Store Associate (Part time)

- Sales and product expert on Saturday shifts and as backup on busy weekdays
  - Developed and inspired connections to our brand, offerings and sport to our clientele

# Feb 2011 - Fulfillment, Receiving, Warehouse management

- Packed customer orders
- Received vendor shipments
- Organized an exponentially growing inventory

### **Education:**

2010, Graduated from Timber Creek High School, Sicklerville, NJ